<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <author>
    <name>Derek Sivers</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://sivers.org/en.atom</id>
  <title>Derek Sivers</title>
  <updated>2018-09-11T06:16:19+01:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	Years ago, I was so confident, and so naive.
	I was so sure that I was right and everyone else was wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Unfortunately I was lucky and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/a&quot;&gt;got successful&lt;/a&gt;, so that kept me ignorant of my shortcomings.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/done&quot;&gt;sold my company&lt;/a&gt;, felt ready to do something new, and started to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book&quot;&gt;learn&lt;/a&gt;.
	But the more I learned, the more I realized how little I knew, and how dumb-lucky I had been.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I continued learning until I felt like an absolute idiot.
	By then I was paralyzed, unable to create anything new.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’d &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/projects&quot;&gt;start to make things&lt;/a&gt;, but then see how stupid they revealed me to be, so I’d stop.
	I lost all confidence.
	I spent a few years completely stuck.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Eventually, some new thoughts helped:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	Learning without doing is wasted.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	If I don’t use what I learn, then it was pointless!
	How horrible to waste those hundreds of hours I spent learning, and not turn it into action.
	Like throwing good food in the trash: it’s morally wrong.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/you-not-them&quot;&gt;
	This isn’t about me.
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;
	How I feel in this moment doesn’t matter — it will pass.
	Nobody is judging me, because nobody is thinking of me.
	They are just looking for things to improve their own life.
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/publicu&quot;&gt;The public me is not the real me&lt;/a&gt; anyway, so if they judge my public persona, that’s fine.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	The work is the point, and my work is unique.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	If I can do something that people find useful, then I should.
	It doesn’t matter if it’s a masterpiece or not, as long as I enjoy it.
	I’ve got my own weird angle on things that’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/counter&quot;&gt;a useful counter-melody&lt;/a&gt; in the big orchestra of life.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So I’m glad my old confidence is gone, because it thought I was right, and maybe even great.
	But I quit that contest.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Now I aim to make my work — my little contribution to the world — just unique and useful.
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/contrib</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/contrib"/>
    <title>You don’t need confidence, just contribution.</title>
    <updated>2018-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	The world changes.
	Some people don’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You learned things that were true back then, but now they’re false.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You got successful doing things one way, but now that way is moot.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You still consider yourself an expert, but that expertise has expired.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You dug so deep into something that you lost perspective, and didn’t realize the landscape had changed.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Sometimes it’s just a change in situation.
	The strategy that got you to where you are is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/switch&quot;&gt;different&lt;/a&gt; from the strategy that will get you to where you want to be next.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	The solution for all of these is unlearning.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Doubt each old thing you know.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Require current evidence.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Make it prove itself to be true today.
	Otherwise, let it go.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Yes I’m talking to myself.
	For ten years I was so deep in &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/a&quot;&gt;my little world of CD Baby&lt;/a&gt; that I lost all perspective.
	I learned so much about the music business in the 90s, then spoke like an expert about it for years, until I suddenly realized that the world had changed so what I was saying wasn’t true anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Since then, when I’m asked for my opinion about the music business, I just say, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/no-oracle&quot;&gt;I don’t know&lt;/a&gt;.”
	It feels weird to say that when someone is looking to me for answers, but I know my old opinions have expired, so I can’t trust those anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	It hurts to go from feeling like an expert to feeling like an idiot.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	But it’s crucial to go through that pain, or you’ll never grow.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This is a modern situation that’s here to stay.
	Technology will keep changing the world faster, so we’ll have to keep unlearning what we knew, and relearning anew.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/crutches.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	P.S. Two great quotes about this:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
	“The illiterates of the 21st century will not be those who cannot read and write but those who cannot learn, unlearn, and relearn.”
— Alvin Toffler
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;
	“I can’t understand why people are frightened of new ideas. I’m frightened of the old ones.”
— John Cage
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/unlearning</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/unlearning"/>
    <title>Unlearning</title>
    <updated>2018-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	The only operating system I use on my computers is &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/itunes&quot;&gt;not Mac&lt;/a&gt;, not Windows, and not even Linux.
	It’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/&quot;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;, and I love it so much.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/63.html&quot;&gt;OpenBSD 6.3&lt;/a&gt; is out now, I figured I should say a little something about why I love it, and how you can try it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	It’s probably not for you.
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	It’s not for beginners.
	Most people should use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntu.com/desktop&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s not for people who want to click a button and have the computer hide the details from you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If software bloat doesn’t bother you — if every new Mac/Windows/Linux release you say, “Bring on the features! The more the better!” — it’s not for you.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But if you’re experienced, like to “look under the hood”, and prefer software that does the minimum necessary, OpenBSD is for you.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	What is it?
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	It’s like Linux, but has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/goals.html&quot;&gt;different goals&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s known for its focus on security.
	But, like a well-engineered house will also be earthquake-proof, you don’t have to be paranoid about earthquakes to appreciate great construction.
	To me, the security features are just a side-effect of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/security.html&quot;&gt;great coding&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	OpenBSD comes with a secure minimal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nostarch.com/pf3&quot;&gt;firewall&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.romanzolotarev.com/openbsd/httpd.html&quot;&gt;webserver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensmtpd.org/&quot;&gt;mailserver&lt;/a&gt;, and an optional graphical &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xenocara.org/&quot;&gt;desktop&lt;/a&gt;.
	So if all you want is a few of those things, you do the default install, tweak one config file, and you’re done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	Why OpenBSD instead of Linux?
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	It’s &lt;strong&gt;uncompromising&lt;/strong&gt;.
	It’s not a people-pleaser or vendor-pleaser.
	Linux is in everything from Android phones to massive supercomputers, so has to include features for all of them.
	The OpenBSD developers say no to most things.
	Instead of trying to make it do more, they keep it focused on doing what it does with more security and reliability.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	They &lt;strong&gt;review and remove&lt;/strong&gt; code as often as they add.
	If something is unused, unmaintained, or unnecessary, they’ll axe it.
	If it’s unwieldy, they’ll make a &lt;strong&gt;small simple replacement&lt;/strong&gt;.
	For examples, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tedunangst.com/flak/post/doas&quot;&gt;doas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opensmtpd.org/&quot;&gt;OpenSMTPD&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/httpd.8&quot;&gt;httpd&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libressl.org/&quot;&gt;LibreSSL&lt;/a&gt;.
	This is great for security, too.
	The more code, the more chance of a bug that could compromise your entire computer.
	The less code, the better.
	Each new release seems to be getting &lt;strong&gt;leaner&lt;/strong&gt; by removing old cruft.
	No other operating system does that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Great &lt;strong&gt;documentation&lt;/strong&gt; is a top priority.
	The built-in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Man_page&quot;&gt;man pages&lt;/a&gt; are amazing.
	So if you’re stuck on anything, &lt;a href=&quot;http://man.openbsd.org/apropos.1&quot;&gt;searching&lt;/a&gt; the man pages on your own computer is going to give you a better answer than searching Google.
	(This makes it nicer to work offline, too.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The &lt;strong&gt;installers&lt;/strong&gt; are amazing.
	The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq4.html&quot;&gt;initial installation&lt;/a&gt; takes like five minutes.
	Hit [Enter] to the defaults, make your username and password, and it’s ready to go.
	Then the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/faq/faq15.html&quot;&gt;software installer&lt;/a&gt; is ideal, too.
	Just &lt;a href=&quot;https://man.openbsd.org/pkg_info.1&quot;&gt;pkg_info&lt;/a&gt; to search for something and &lt;a href=&quot;http://man.openbsd.org/pkg_add.1&quot;&gt;pkg_add&lt;/a&gt; to install it in seconds.
	(Which also installs all of its documentation, too.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Everything is rock-solid and &lt;strong&gt;just works&lt;/strong&gt;.
	Hardware I couldn’t get working in Linux just works on a first try with OpenBSD.
	And because they don’t stay cutting-edge, keeping a cautious pace, it keeps working and doesn’t break.
	The whole system is carefully planned and consistent, instead of a hodge-podge of bits and pieces.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s all free and run by helpful volunteers.
	If you &lt;a href=&quot;http://cvsweb.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/cvsweb/ports/&quot;&gt;searched ports&lt;/a&gt;, but some application you need is missing or out of date, just contact the maintainer and offer some assistance or money to help get it updated or added.
	I’ve donated $3500 to the developers to help improve the OpenBSD port of &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://elixir-lang.org/&quot;&gt;Elixir&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.erlang.org/&quot;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ledger-cli.org/&quot;&gt;Ledger&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qutebrowser.org/&quot;&gt;Qutebrowser&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	Now, how?
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This is where I could say, “So go to openbsd.org and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbsd.org/63.html&quot;&gt;give it a try&lt;/a&gt;! Bye!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But since I’ve tweaked a great setup over the years, I wrapped up some of my instructions and config files for you here:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	If you want to play with OpenBSD on a public-facing server, I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vultr.com/&quot;&gt;Vultr&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	And once you’ve got it installed, type this command …
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ftp &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/file/63.tar&quot;&gt;https://sivers.org/file/63.tar&lt;/a&gt; ; tar xf 63.tar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
	… and you’ll have my personal shortcuts I use for setting up my OpenBSD 6.3 desktop.
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/openbsd.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/openbsd</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/openbsd"/>
    <title>OpenBSD 6.3 : why and how</title>
    <updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	At &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book&quot;&gt;sivers.org/book&lt;/a&gt; I have a collection of my notes from the 250+ books I’ve read since 2007.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This page is just to answer some questions about it.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	My notes are not a summary of the book!
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	When I’m reading and come across a surprising or inspiring idea, I save it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	That’s all my notes are.
	I’m not summarizing the book.
&lt;strong&gt;
	I’m just saving ideas for myself, for later reflection.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If I’m reading a book about a subject I already know well, I’ll have very few notes, because not much surprised me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I kept these notes private for years, but decided it couldn’t hurt to put them on my site.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	Notes don’t replace the book
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	It makes me sad when people email to say thanks for my notes because it saved them time from reading the book.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	My notes are just some tiny tidbits with no context.
&lt;strong&gt;
	It’s like reading a punchline without the joke.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	If you hear an elaborate joke, then the punchline — (“The little piece of rope said, ‘No. I’m a frayed knot!’”) — is all you need to remember the full joke.
	But if you just hear the punchline, without the joke, it makes no sense.
	I just save the punchlines to remind myself what I’ve read.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Again: these notes are really just for me but I’m sharing them on my site.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If you look through a book’s notes and like the ideas, please go read the whole book.
	It gives so much more context and meaning.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	“How do you use these notes?”
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This will always be changing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For the past few years, when I have a few minutes, I’ll just pick some book from the past that might apply to a situation I’m working on now, and re-read all the notes on it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’ve also used them to research a certain subject, like discipline for example, I’ll go search all notes for any mention of discipline, and re-read the thoughts on that subject.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Eventually instead of them being saved in a single text file per-book, I’m going to feed each individual idea into a &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.sivers.org/db-api/lat/&quot;&gt;database&lt;/a&gt;, tagged, so I can use some interesting lateral thinking tools.
	I set up the software to do this, but it’s going to be very time consuming, because most ideas will need editing to become stand-alone ideas, not needing the context of the notes before and after them.
	So for 250 books, about 100 ideas per book, that’s 25,000 ideas I need to edit.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	“Why don’t I see __(some book)___?”
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	I do read fiction, but I don’t take notes on it.
	For fiction, I prefer audiobook.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I also read hundreds of books before 2007, but didn’t start taking notes until I realized I was forgetting what I had read.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	And ultimately, I only read things that apply to my life or current interests right now.
	I say no to all requests, and publishers asking me to do reviews.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	“Which one should I read?”
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Whichever one seems to apply to your current situation.
	I find books most useful when they solve a problem I’m having now.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	By default I have &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book&quot;&gt;the list&lt;/a&gt; sorted with my top recommendations up top.
	But really the best one for you is the one that speaks to your current situation.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	“Don’t the authors get mad?”
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	No, but this was my biggest surprise!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The main reason I didn’t post these for years is because I assumed it was against copyright law.
	But I quietly tried it, without announcing it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then as the site got more popular, I was scared I’d get in trouble, but instead I got emails of thanks from the authors of those books.
	Maybe especially since I really am trying to get people to go buy the books whose notes they like.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	“Exactly how do you take these notes?”
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	When reading a paper book, I just underline or circle the bits I find surprising or useful.
	Then when I’m done reading the book, I type those bits into a text file.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	On Kindle, I just highlight the bits I find surprising or useful.
	Then when I’m done reading the book, I connect the Kindle by USB, copy the «/documents/My Clippings.txt» file, and edit from there.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Either way, I tend to edit a lot, and re-shape the sentences into something that works for me.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	“Hey you might like this other book summary site!”
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	No.
	I don’t want to read summaries of books.
	I like reading the whole book!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I aim to read even harder books, like “&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book/HowToReadABook&quot;&gt;How to Read a Book&lt;/a&gt;” describes well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;
	Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book&quot;&gt;sivers.org/book&lt;/a&gt; to browse the notes.
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/book&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/bookstand.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/bfaq</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/bfaq"/>
    <title>about my book notes</title>
    <updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	You are the way you are because of what you’ve experienced.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Your country, family, town, random circumstances, and friends shaped the way you think.
	If you grew up on the other side of the world, you would have a different set of values and thought patterns.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But if you keep experiencing the same things, your mind keeps its same patterns.
	Same input, same response.
	Your brain, which was once curious and growing, gets fixed into deep habits.
	Your values and opinions harden and resist change.
	If you don’t flex, you lose your flexibility.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You only really learn when you’re surprised.
	Unless you’re surprised, everything is fitting into your existing thought patterns.
	So to get smarter, you need to get surprised, think in new ways, and deeply understand different perspectives.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	With effort, you could do this from the comforts of home.
&lt;strong&gt;
	But the most effective way to shake things up is to move across the world.
	Pick a place that’s most unlike what you know, and go.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This keeps you in a learning mindset.
	Previously mindless habits, like buying groceries, now keep your mind open, alert, and noticing new things.
	New arrivals in a culture often notice what the locals don’t.
	(&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/fish&quot;&gt;Fish don’t know they’re in water.&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Don’t think of yourself as visiting.
	Say that you’ve moved here, and mean it.
	Commit.
	Immerse.
	Go native.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Form deep friendships with locals.
	Ask lots of questions.
	Ask them to explain things, and show you how it’s done.
	When they state a fact, ask how they know.
	When they state an opinion, ask for examples.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	At first, their values and methods will feel wrong.
	You’ll feel the urge to tell them how it could be better.
	(Meaning: more like what you know.)
	But try to understand a perspective where they are right, and you are wrong.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Eventually you’ll realize that your beliefs were not correct — they were just the quaint local culture of where you grew up.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	You are a product of your environment.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Every country has a shared and working philosophy.
	Dive in and really try to understand it.
	This is one of the best things you can do for your brain.
	Stay immersed at least until you feel yourself saying “we” instead of “they”.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then, if you want to keep your brain actively learning and growing forever, keep moving across the world and immersing like this for the rest of your life.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;
	(I wrote this for Tynan’s new book “&lt;a href=&quot;http://tynan.com/forevernomad&quot;&gt;Forever Nomad&lt;/a&gt;”, so please &lt;a href=&quot;http://tynan.com/forevernomad&quot;&gt;buy his book&lt;/a&gt; if you like this subject.)
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://tynan.com/forevernomad&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Forever Nomad&quot; src=&quot;/images/forevernomad.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/mfg</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/mfg"/>
    <title>Moving for good</title>
    <updated>2018-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-03-31T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	I tried Facebook for a few weeks in 2007, but I hadn’t really used it since then.
	I would log in once a month for a few minutes and click [ACCEPT] to all the friend requests from strangers, then log out.
	I hit the 5000 friend-limit, so I created a second profile.
	That hit the 5000 friend-limit too, so I created a third.
	When the third one hit the friend-limit, I stopped.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I thought I was just being polite, accepting friend requests, but I didn’t know who most of them were.
&lt;strong&gt;
	It was very insincere.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	When real friends would ask if I’m on Facebook, I’d have to explain, “It looks like I’m there, but not really there.”
	I never posted anything personal, and never installed it on my phone.
	I was really just using it to announce new blog posts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When people would do their “&lt;a href=&quot;https://deletefacebook.com/&quot;&gt;DELETE FACEBOOK!&lt;/a&gt;” campaigns, I didn’t bother because I wasn’t using it anyway.
&lt;strong&gt;
	It was causing me no harm.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	I think it’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=facebook&amp;amp;sites=calnewport.com&amp;amp;ia=web&quot;&gt;net-negative for the world, and causing many people harm&lt;/a&gt;, but not me, so why bother deleting it?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	But the more I thought about it, the less I liked my implied support.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	I’m sick of being insincere.
	I’m against centralized platforms.
	I strongly prefer a &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/&quot;&gt;decentralized internet&lt;/a&gt;.
	I’m always helping friends get off of the big platforms and on to their own servers.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Maybe the fact that I use Facebook to share my blog posts is a tiny tiny reason why others are still using it.
	It’s like I’m still visiting friends in the smoking area, even though I don’t smoke.
	Maybe if I quit going entirely, it will help my friends quit, too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	So I snapped out of the silly fear that people won’t find me if I’m not there.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	If they care at all, they’ll find me.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So, yeah.
	That decided it.
	I deleted all three accounts with 15,000 “friends”.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I had a selfish business reason to keep it.
	I’m going to be publishing three different books over the next year, and plan to launch a new business, too.
&lt;strong&gt;
	But I’m willing to take that small loss in promotion, because &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.seanbonner.com/2012/04/15/on-leaving-facebook/&quot;&gt;it’s the right thing to do&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	It always feels good to get rid of things I’m not using.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I’ve been online since 1994.
	I remember when everyone thought mp3.com was everything, and a few years later it was gone.
	Then everyone thought MySpace was everything, and a few years later it was moot.
	Now it’s Facebook, Instagram, and Google, but eventually they’ll all be moot, too.
	It’s the natural cycle of things.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/adoption_life_cycle-500x414.jpg&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/facebook</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/facebook"/>
    <title>Why I’m not on Facebook</title>
    <updated>2018-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	There’s a fable of a man stuck in a flood.
	Convinced that God is going to save him, he says no to a passing canoe, boat, and helicopter that offer to help.
	He dies, and in heaven asks God why He didn’t save him.
	God says, “I sent you a canoe, a boat, and a helicopter!”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	We all have vivid imaginations.
	We get a goal in our mind and picture the path so clearly.
	Then it’s hard to stop focusing on that vivid image, to see what else could work.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	New technologies make old things easier, and new things possible.
&lt;strong&gt;
	That’s why you need to re-evaluate your old dreams to see if new means have come along.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Some actors move to Hollywood hoping to get noticed.
	Others use every new outlet to make themselves unavoidable.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Some authors are just waiting for a publisher to sign them.
	Others are getting rich just self-publishing.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You need to distinguish between what is your real goal, and what are the unnecessary details.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Don’t let the details distract you from your goal.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For each of your dreams, occasionally ask yourself what the real point is.
	Then look for a better way to get to that point.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Let go of outdated dreams that keep you from noticing what’s here now.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/stork.jpg&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/details</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/details"/>
    <title>Detailed dreams blind you to new means.</title>
    <updated>2018-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	Everyone who is drawn to you before you’re famous is thinking the same thing:
&lt;strong&gt;
	You might be famous soon!
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	fans who want to help you
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	professionals who want to meet you
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	musicians who want to play with you
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	companies that want to work with you
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	They’re all hoping to be included in your glorious future.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	As you get more successful, share that success with those who helped you years ago.
	When you’re in the tornado of fame, you can’t depend on your memory.
	So use your database now to keep track of who has done special favors for you.
&lt;strong&gt;
	When you are famous, return the favors.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Reach out to contact them, and invite them into your new world.
	(Don’t wait for them to ask.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Those that gave their services for free?
	Now you can pay full price.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Those who wanted glamour by association?
	Invite them to the best party.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Those who deserve more recognition?
	Shout their praises to your new audience.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	You aren’t pulled to success by destiny.
	You’re lifted there by those around you.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	So acknowledge their contribution, and bring them along for the ride.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/include-everyone.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/inclev</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/inclev"/>
    <title>Include everyone in your success.</title>
    <updated>2018-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	This is what I do for &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/blog&quot;&gt;everything I post&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Write all of my thoughts on a subject.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Argue against those ideas.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Explore different angles until I’m sick of it.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Leave it for a few days or years, then repeat those steps.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Hate how messy these thoughts have become.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	Reduce them to a tiny outline of the key points.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	Post the outline. Trash the rest.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/birdinthehand/214326064/&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/trash3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/birdinthehand/214326064/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;trash photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/birdinthehand/&quot;&gt;Lisa Congdon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/7</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/7"/>
    <title>My writing process</title>
    <updated>2018-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	When I was promoting myself as a musician, I noticed an interesting pattern.
	If I had a good conversation with somebody in the music business, then quite often they would send an opportunity my way within a day or two.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	In other words, when I look back at the random opportunities that came my way, they often came from someone who I had just spoken with a day or two before.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Yes I just said this twice to emphasize it.
	This is important.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Years later, when I was running CD Baby, various opportunities came up where someone asked me to recommend a musician.
	I almost always recommended whichever musician I had just spoken with, since they came to mind first.
	That’s why it’s so important to keep in touch.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	There were some amazing musicians whose music I loved, so I contacted them to tell them I’m a huge fan, and would love to help however I can.
	But if they didn’t keep in touch, they eventually fell out of my mind.
	It’s unfortunate, but that’s life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	There were some good (but not amazing) musicians who were great at keeping in touch.
	So when opportunities came my way, guess who I thought of to recommend?
	Yep.
	That’s life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	The difference between success and failure can be as simple as keeping in touch. 
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It takes effort to meet people.
	So once you’ve met someone, get the most out of the relationship for both of you.
	Keep in touch.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/keep-in-touch.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/kit</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/kit"/>
    <title>Keep in touch.</title>
    <updated>2018-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	This is both fun and considerate.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When people say that a movie has a great character, they mean it was someone especially shocking, funny, or honest.
	To be a great entertainer, you need to be larger than life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Push your outer boundaries.
	Show your weirdness.
	Bring out all your quirks.
	The world needs that.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	Your public persona — the image you show the world — should be an extreme character.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	It can be a version of yourself, or it can be a mask.
	(It’s easier to be honest behind a mask.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Some of the biggest musicians of the last few decades have admitted they were playing a character.
	Eminem, for example, said he wrote lyrics with the goal of shocking a passive listener into paying attention.
	Then he built his public persona to match the lyrics.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Are you concerned that maybe you should play it safe, because your music isn’t so extreme?
	Well… 
	Think of the conservative, old-fashioned performers that your great-grandmother probably liked.
Frank Sinatra.
Judy Garland.
Miles Davis.
Billie Holiday.
	Even these old legends were rather extreme.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	It’s more interesting for the audience if you’re the opposite of normal.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	So be an extreme character.
	The spotlight is the excuse.
	You can get away with anything in the name of entertainment.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/extreme-version.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/evers</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/evers"/>
    <title>Be an extreme character.</title>
    <updated>2018-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	This is one of the most useful lessons I’ve learned in life.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When you don’t know your next step…
&lt;br/&gt;
	When you’re feeling unmotivated…
&lt;br/&gt;
	When asking someone to help you…
&lt;br/&gt;
	When you’re ready to make a dream come true…
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	Get more specific about what’s needed.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	There are two ways to do it:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	#1: Write down every detail you know.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Inside your head, there is more than you’ve said.
	Take the time to write it all down.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When you have a vague or distant goal — like “be a great singer” or “make a million from my music” — break it down into specific ingredients.
	Describe concrete milestones, and exactly how to reach them.
	Then break those down into actions that you can start doing today.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When you’re feeling stuck or unmotivated, figure out your next step.
	Even something as simple as finishing a song is easier when you realize exactly what’s wrong.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When you hire someone to help you, write down absolutely everything you need them to do.
	Include every detail of every step, and your philosophy too.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	#2: Research what you don’t know.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Most people know what they want, but don’t know how to get it.
	When you don’t know the next step, you procrastinate or feel lost.
	But a little research can turn a vague desire into specific actions.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For example:
	When musicians say, “I need a booking agent”, I ask, “Which one? What’s their name?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	You can’t act on a vague desire.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	But with an hour of research you could find the names of ten booking agents that work with ten artists you admire.
	Then you’ve got a list of the next ten people you need to contact.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A life coach told me that most of his job is just helping people get specific.
	Once they turn a vague goal into a list of specific steps, it’s easy to take action.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	It also makes you realize if something was a bad idea.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Many things only sound nice in theory.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So do this for yourself.
	Take the time to get specific. 
	It helps you and others to take action, and beats procrastination.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/footsteps.jpg&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/get-specific</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/get-specific"/>
    <title>Get specific!</title>
    <updated>2018-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	I was at a musicians’ gathering in Memphis.
	I met a lot of people complaining that their various forms of online distribution weren’t earning them as much as they’d hoped.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then I met a musician who sold 8000 copies of his album himself.
	No distributor.
	No website.
	Just by himself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I asked him how he did it.
	He said, “&lt;strong&gt;I just slowly drove around the city every night, with the windows down, playing my music loud. When I saw someone digging it, I’d go talk with them. I’d sell almost everyone a copy — about 20 or 30 a night. Been doing this about a year. Sold 8000 so far.&lt;/strong&gt;”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I love this story!
	It’s so direct!
	It hit me especially hard because all the musicians I’d met before him were complaining about how it’s impossible to make money anymore.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It got me thinking about what it means to be resourceful.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The succinct way to show it is to contrast two different mindsets.
	I’ll call them A and B.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “I spent $60,000 making this album.”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “I spent $60 making this album.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “There are no good live music venues anymore!”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “I made us a new venue.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “I’ve tried everything.”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “I found a book from the 1970s with some unique ideas I’m applying to our marketing.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “I don’t have time to do it all!”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “Two of my fans help with promotion, one edits my videos, and one runs my website.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “I’m not some Hollywood networking dude. I don’t have connections in the industry.”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “My barber knew the promoter’s wife, so it took some persistence, but now we’re playing at his festival.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “They said we weren’t allowed to just show up.”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “We just showed up, and wouldn’t leave. Eventually they said OK.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “We didn’t get the festival gig.”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “They rejected us, so we contacted every artist at the festival until we found one that insisted the promoter book us as their opening act.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	A: “There’s just no way!”
&lt;br/&gt;
	B: “I figured out a way.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	It means being creative, rebellious, determined, and unstoppable.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	It means asking for help, but not waiting for help.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/res.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;illustration ©2018 John Warner&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/res</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/res"/>
    <title>What it means to be resourceful</title>
    <updated>2018-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	I was 20 years old.
	I had just moved to New York City.
	And I was working inside the music industry.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I ran the music library at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.warnerchappell.com/&quot;&gt;Warner/Chappell&lt;/a&gt;.
	It was a huge room, near the executives’ offices, and I had it all to myself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Rock stars would come into my room before or after their meetings, to wait or relax.
	Because I was just some nobody working in the library, they would often speak candidly.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	What surprised me was this:
&lt;strong&gt;
	These rock stars’ biggest complaints were about the things they were forced to do, or not allowed to do!
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Things like, “I think the album is perfect and finished, but the label says they don’t hear a hit, so they’re making me co-write.”
	Or, “I wanted to make a video with this director I admire, but the label won’t let me.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I had always assumed that rock stars were the top of the food chain.
	It was weird to realize they had a boss!
&lt;strong&gt;
	But that’s the trade-off when you sign away your rights.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The independent music revolution was so exciting because thousands of musicians were realizing that they didn’t need to sign these kinds of deals anymore.
	They didn’t need labels, distributors, publishers, or anything else to get their music to the public.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But years later, I still hear people making that trade-off.
	Giving up their rights and serving a company, in hopes of a greater reward.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	authors who act like Amazon is the boss
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	web designers who act like Google is the boss
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
	promoters who act like Facebook is the boss
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	But you only have a boss if you choose to!
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Nobody is making you serve these masters.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Of course, if you don’t want a boss, then everything is up to you.
	Less promotion, but more freedom.
	Less help, but keeping all your rights.
	Riding the back roads, not the highway.
	Serving no one but yourself.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Never forget you have the choice.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/creative-business.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/noboss</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/noboss"/>
    <title>Rock stars have a boss?</title>
    <updated>2018-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	One of the top music industry lawyers in Los Angeles was speaking at a conference.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	She’s an expert in copyright law, so someone asked her advice on a licensing problem.
	They had recorded their version of a famous song, but were unable to get the rights to sell it because they couldn’t get a response from the publisher.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The lawyer shocked the audience when she said, “Sell it anyway.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Don’t wait for permission.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Save the proof that you tried your best to reach them.
	If they contact you to ask for money some day, pay them then.
	But never wait.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Coming from a copyright lawyer, that was a bold statement.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It was a reminder that your career is more important than its details.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Success is your top priority.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Never let anything stop you.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/nowclock.jpg&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/neverwait</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/neverwait"/>
    <title>Never wait.</title>
    <updated>2018-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	Psychology experiments have shown that the more people pay for something, the more they value it.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	People given a placebo pill were twice as likely to have their pain disappear when they were told that the pill was expensive.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	People who paid more for tickets were more likely to attend the performance. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When people want the best, they look to the price to tell them what’s great.
	They think the expensive wine tastes better.
	They think the expensive headphones sound better.
	Even when secretly, those things are no different than the cheap ones.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If you sign a deal with a company, negotiate the biggest up-front advance possible.
	Even if you don’t need the money, it’s the best strategy, because the higher your advance, the harder the company will work to earn it back.
	It ends up being better for everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Tony Robbins, back when he was first getting successful, started charging one million dollars for personal consultations.
	His reason was surprising.
	It wasn’t for the money.
	It was because his goal was to help people improve their life, and his biggest problem was people not doing the necessary work after coming to see him.
	So if someone spends a million dollars, they’re sure as hell going to do the work.
	He says it kept his success rate at 100%.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	So it’s considerate to charge more for your work.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	People will appreciate it more, and get better results.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/wineglass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/mr_t_in_dc/3000950461/&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/morepay</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/morepay"/>
    <title>The higher the price, the more they value it.</title>
    <updated>2018-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	The way you communicate with people is part of your art.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	For people who have never heard your music, it’s the &lt;em&gt;start&lt;/em&gt; of your art!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If you make depressing music, send your fans a dark black announcement that’s depressing just to look at.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	If you are an “in-your-face country-metal-speedpunk” artist, have the guts to call a potential booking agent and scream, “Listen you crazy dirtbag! Book me or I explode! Waaaaaah!!”
	If they like that introduction, you’ve found a good match.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Set the tone.
	Pull in those people who love that kind of thing.
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/exclude&quot;&gt;Proudly alienate&lt;/a&gt; those that don’t.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	There’s a minimalist classical music composer whose emails to me are always just one provocative thought.
	Like when I posted something online about being an introvert, he emailed me just one sentence:
	“Are we not ever-changing, both gradually and per situation?”
	That’s it.
	No greeting or closing or manners in-between.
	His communication style always makes me smile, and reminds me of his music.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The gentle new-age artist always calls me “sweetie” and reminds me to nourish my soul.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The surf-music artist always uses the Hawaiian greetings “aloha” and “mahalo” when he emails, along with other surfer slang.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The rebellious punk never calls me by my name, but instead just says, “Hey sellout.”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Be different.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Show who you are.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It gives people’s lives more variety, too.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/reach-like-you.gif&quot;&gt;

</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/reach</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/reach"/>
    <title>Creative communication</title>
    <updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	You get a big long email from someone and think, “Ooof. I’ll come back to that later.”
	(Then you never do.)
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Someone tries to contact you using a technology you hate, like a surprising incoming video call.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You have a dilemma and need a good conversation, so you reach out to someone who replies, “Can you make it quick?”
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	You’re overwhelmed with work on a tight deadline, and a friend calls trying to have a long conversation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It’s hard to match your communication with someone else’s preference and situation.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	There’s a huge benefit to having a great conversation, but sometimes you need to be extremely succinct.
	So how do you reconcile this?
	Here’s my advice:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	First, prepare the most succinct version of your reason for contacting someone.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Make it so short that if the person only has 30 seconds to talk, you could communicate your point, ask your question, and get the answer.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	With real-time communication, like text or phone, just start by asking if they have time.
	If they do, then take the time to get personal, be a friend, and have a good conversation.
	But if they don’t, then just use the short version.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	With non-real-time communication, like email, assume you’ve only got ten seconds.
&lt;strong&gt;
	Edit your emails down to a few sentences.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	But always give a link to more information, so they can check it out if they have time.
	And include your other contact information, in case they prefer a longer conversation about it.
	(This is what email signatures are for.)
	Then, if they reply and ask, you can give the extra information you left out before.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Some hate texting.
	Some hate calls.
	Some hate video.
	Some hate it all.
	Just keep track of their preference for future use.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	This may sound obvious, but it’s a bigger problem than people realize.
	Considerate communication is surprisingly rare.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/reach-like-you.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/ccom</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/ccom"/>
    <title>Considerate communication</title>
    <updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	Before I got into the music industry, I had an idea of what it would look like:
	Some powerful manager or agent calling me into his office to discuss the business of my music.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Then I moved to New York City and became friends with cool people who also did things in music.
	Sometimes these people were agents or managers, but that was secondary.
	Mostly we were just friends.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Sometimes I’d send them clients.
	Sometimes they’d hook me up with opportunities.
	But really we were just friends, talking about our love lives or ideas, hanging out and having fun.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	It was a long time before I realized that I was already in the industry — that this is how things are done.
&lt;strong&gt;
	People send business to people they like.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	It’s all more personal than I had expected.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	One of my best friends in the world is also my lawyer.
	He’s one of the top music lawyers in the world, but mostly he’s my friend.
	We talk about cycling, his kids, and music.
	And sometimes we stop to discuss a recent contract.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	The initial contact usually happens for professional reasons.
	Like when I was looking for a lawyer, and someone introduced me to this guy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	When I hear music I love, I contact the musician, and say let’s meet.
	Within minutes we’re talking about her dogs, microphones, Japan, and whatever.
	Then, when someone asks me to recommend some music, guess who comes to mind first?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Point is:
	As you’re out there in the music business, get personal.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Don’t always be selling yourself.
	That keeps people at a distance from you, because it shows you’re not friends.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	Even if it starts professional, get personal as soon as possible.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	Be a friend.
	That’s how things are done.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/get-personal.gif&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/gpers</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/gpers"/>
    <title>Get personal.</title>
    <updated>2018-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
	I was a struggling musician, with big ambitions but not much success, when I went to a music industry conference in Las Vegas to promote my music.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I was nervous, but doing everything I could to make connections with the managers at all the big music companies.
	I attended every panel of experts, noting everyone’s name, and approaching the stage afterwards to introduce myself.
&lt;strong&gt;
	I had these people up on a pedestal.
	I was terrified of them.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	The stakes were high.
	These were the people who could make my career.
	It was mentally and emotionally exhausting.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So during lunch I went out to the pool and stuck my feet in the water, just to silently retreat.
	Some dude sat next to me and did the same.
	He said, “I see you’ve noticed the bikini girls, too.”
	I had.
	So we sat there, feet in the pool, talking about those girls over there, how weird Las Vegas is, how his friend was up all night gambling, and other random chit-chat.
	He was a really cool dude — the rare kind I just click with right away.
	I assumed he must be a fellow musician.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	But when he got up to leave, he said, “Really great talking with you. Let’s keep in touch,” and handed me his business card.
	Holy shit!
	He was the vice president of one of the biggest record labels!
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I learned a huge lesson that day.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
	If I would have known who he was in advance, I never would have had a real conversation with him.
&lt;/strong&gt;
	I would have been awkward and self-conscious, trying to promote myself.
	But because I didn’t know, I could connect on a personal level, and be a real friend.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	I used to think that having connections in the music industry meant that you’d have business meetings, and only talk about your mutual business interests.
	But again and again I’ve realized that we make real connections by talking about anything else, and just clicking as friends.
&lt;strong&gt;
	People send business to people they like.
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	So beware of putting people on a pedestal.
	It can prevent a real friendship.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
	Postscript to this story:
	We kept in touch, and he ended up sending me some of my most successful CD Baby clients.
	Now, twenty years later, I just emailed him to tell him I’m writing this story.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/pedestal.jpg&quot; title=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/caochopp/7028335609&quot;&gt;
</content>
    <id>https://sivers.org/pedestal</id>
    <link href="https://sivers.org/pedestal"/>
    <title>Pedestals prevent friendships.</title>
    <updated>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <dc:date>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</dc:date>
  </entry>
  <dc:date>2018-09-11T06:16:19+01:00</dc:date>
</feed>
